Guide to the Prize Essay Collection, 1872-2017
Prize Essay Collection, 1872-2017
- Series X. Goethe Prize Essays
  - First place, freshman/sophomore: Analyse von Richard Huelsenbecks Gedicht "Dada-Schalmei," auf Seite 128, Dada Total. Das Gedicht kann auch auf der letzten Seite gefunden werden. Gregoriy A. Dokshin, 2005 (Box 32)
  - First place, junior/senior: Das Primat des Praktischen in Kants "Grundlegung" Joseph "Jed" Lewinsorn, 2005 (Box 32)
  - Second place, graduate: Heteronomy and Autonomy: Communication Media in Fichte's Encounter with Mesmerism Sean Franzel, 2005 (Box 32)
  - Second place, graduate: "And something evermore about to be.. .": The Proleptic Subject of the Sublime in the Late Writings of Immanual Kant Robert S. Lehman, 2005 (Box 32)
  - Second place, sophomore: "The role of political criticism in Goethe's Egmont and Schiller's Don Carlos and Wilhelm Tell" Myrtle McClintock [Daniela White], 2006 (Box 32)
  - First place, senior: "Vergleich und Analyse von der Kritik der Avantgarde": The Proleptic Subject of the Sublime in the Late Writings of Immanual Kant Maximillian Hugenpoet [Michael J. Lander], 2006 (Box 32)
  - Second place, senior: "Soames on Wittgenstein: Unpacking the Private Language Argument" [Wesley Mattingly], 2006 (Box 32)
  - First place, graduate: "The Reduction and the Ruin of the Human: Jean Amery, the Experience of Torture, and the Writing of Pain" Austerlitz [Melanie Steiner], 2006 (Box 32)
  - Second place, graduate: "Siegfried Kracauer and Bertolt Brecht: A Dialogue on the Author in the Age of Mass Media" [Erica Doerhoff], 2006 (Box 32)
  - First place, Freshman/Sophomore: "Analysis of Franz Kafka's 'A Fasting Artist,'" John Smith [Ismael Amaro], 2007 (Box 32)
  - Second place, Junior/Senior: "Goethe's Challenge," Friedrich Schiller [Somone Glanert], 2007 (Box 32)
  - Second place, Junior/Senior: "Preserving the Best of Faust: ergo scripendium est," A. Scott [Amanda Guise], 2007 (Box 32)
  - First place, Graduate: "Nach Selbstportraits von Käthe Kollwitz," Anja Brandt [Stephanie Gehring], 2007 (Box 32)
  - First place, Graduate: "Grounding Place: Temporal Plasticity in Hölderling's Nachgesänge and Der Winkel von Hardt," "Grad" [Alexis Briley], 2007 (Box 32)
  - First place, Graduate: "The Composer's Canvas: CPE Bach, Pictorialism, and German Enlightenment Aesthetics" Katherine H. Walker, "Grad", 2008 (Box 32)
  - First place, Graduate: "Aisthetische Literarizität - eine Provokation für die Literaturwissenschaft?", Adalbert Wurst "Grad" [Christian Jany], 2008 (Box 32)
  - Second place, Graduate: "Intervention of the Narrator in 'Sine Klâwen,'" Rubin Heritagio "Grad" [Paul Buchholz], 2008 (Box 32)
  - First place, Junior/Senior: "Die Familie als Erinnerung in 'Am Beispiel meines Bruders'" [Christopher Muenten], 2008 (Box 32)
  - Freshman/Sophomore: "Wie verstehen Faust und Mephistopheles ihre Partnerschaft?" Maren Nordmann [Mallory Matsumoto], 2009 (Box 34)
  - Freshman/Sophomore: "Reconsidering Cross-Species Communication: Kafka, Intramodal Analogy, and the Philosopher des Als Ob" X [Ian Wells], 2009 (Box 34)
  - Graduate: "Wie die Pfeiler gesprengter Brücken": Experience, Memory, and Writing in Ruth Klüger's weiter leben," Walt von der Vogelweide [Ari Linden], 2009 (Box 34)
  - Graduate: "Marx's Politics of Comedy" Rusty Shackleford [Paul Flaig], 2009 (Box 34)
  - Graduate: "How to Read: the perceptual demands of Lázló Moholu-Nagy's new vision and Berthold Brecht's Complex seeing" David Bowie [Katrina Nousek], 2009 (Box 34)
  - Freshman: Character and its Various Implementation in the Writings of Nietzsche" David Hillel [Daniel Kuhr], 2010 (Box 34)
  - Sophomore: "Die Vergleichsanalyse der Gedichten von Paul Celan: 'Zu beiden Handen' und 'Schneebett'" X [Katarzyna Pozniak], 2010 (Box 34)
  - Graduate: "The Organon of Freedom: Schelling's Task for Philosophy" [Klas Molde], 2010 (Box 34)
  - Graduate: "Realism as Fantasy - Performing Space with Stifter and Keller" Henryk Grzynszpan [Carl Gelderloos], 2010 (Box 34)
  - Undergraduate Junior: "Derrida und Gadamar: Verschiedene Analysen von Paul Celan" E. C., Junior [Elizabeth Cai], 2011 (Box 34)
  - Undergraduate Senior: "Die Suche nach Bedeutung in Celans Gedichten" Anonymous 1 [Anna Rady], 2011 (Box 34)
  - Graduate Student: "Toward a concept of historical truth content in literary texts: Rereading Adorno's 'Rede über Lyrik und Gesellschaft" Max Reiser [Johannes Wankhammer], 2011 (Box 34)
  - Third Year Graduate Student: "Uncanny Instruments: T. T. A. Hoffmann and the Musical Uncanny" Lilly Grundner [Amanda Saunders Lalonde], 2011 (Box 34)
  - First place, Graduate: "Herta Müller's Materialism and the Failure of a Realist Aesthetics of Catastrophe" [Matteo Calla], 2012 (Box 34)
  - First place, Junior/Senior: "Dealing with Kant Defensively" [Jason Yanover], 2012 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Junior/Senior: "O ewige Nacht! Wann wrist du schwinden? Searching for the Premier of Die Zauberflöte in Historical Obscurity" [Jason Boada], 2012 (Box 34)
  - First place, Freshman/Sophomore: "Die Rolle der Grund-und Hauptschule Bad Bentheim-Gildehaus beim Erhalt des Niederdeutschen in ihrer Region" [Henry Ekwaro-Osire], 2012 (Box 34)
  - First place, Graduate: "Jus Sanguinis, Jus Soli: West German Citizenship Law and Melodrama of the Guest Worker in Fassbinder's Angst Essen Seele Auf" [Avery Slater], 2013 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Graduate: "Schiller's argument for the Ideal of Humanity: An analysis of Letters 11-16" [Stephen Klemm], 2013 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Graduate: "Am Nullpunkt des Realismus: Terézia Moras Poetik des hic et nunc" [Nathan Taylor], 2013 (Box 34)
  - First place, Junior/Senior: "Der Krimi als 'Surrogat'? Eine Diskussion des modernen deutschen Kriminalromans mit Bezung auf Brecht" [Laura Carver], 2013 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Junior/Senior: "Im Winter der Löwen und The Face on the Cutting-Room Floor: Zwei Interpretationen der Krimi-Gattung" [R. Thora Bjornsdottir], 2013 (Box 34)
  - First place, Freshmen/Sophomore: "Verschiedenen Aspekte des Detektivromans in The Big Sleep und Im Winter der Löwen" [Travis Westura], 2013 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Freshmen/Sophomore: "On the 'Being' behind 'Doing' and the Problem of Free Will in Nietzsche's Genealogy" [Christina Zhang], 2013 (Box 34)
  - First Place, Graduate: "The Righteous in God's Hands: A Funeral Motet as Theological Battleground" [Dietmar Friesenegger], 2014 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Junior/Senior: "Durrenmatt und seine Komodie" [Yuezhou Huo], 2014 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Junior/Senior: "On Fichte's Theory of Property: Liberalism and Egalitarianism" " [Alejandro Naranjo Sandoval], 2014 (Box 34)
  - First place, Junior/Senior: "Reading speechlessness in Tragedy and Traurspiel: Antiquity's Law and Benjamin's Lesson" [Jennifer Dumler], 2014 (Box 34)
  - First place, Junior/Senior: "Moses Mendelssohn:"Historical Without Being Historisist" [Jonathan Barry Schmidt-Swartz], 2015 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Junior/Senior: "Exposing Metaphysical Subject Via Nietzsche's Genealogical Method" [Carolina Iribarren], 2015 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Junior/Senior: "Unhaltbares Gleichgewicht; Amerikanische Auβenpolitik und der Zerfall de Weimarer Republik" [Patrick Molligo], 2015 (Box 34)
  - First place, Freshmen/Sophomore: "The Dead Lyric in the Poetry of Hölderlin & Celan" [Amanda Coate], 2015 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Freshmen/Sophomore: "The Poet's Condition in Relation to Humanity: Understanding Rilke's Second Duino Elegy Through Close Reading" [Eng Liang Daniel Cheong], 2015 (Box 34)
  - First place, Graduate: "Schiller on transgressive realist and idealist characters in On Naive and Sentimental Poetry" [Matthias Muller], 2016 (Box 34)
  - First place, Junior/Senior: "On Benjamin's Philosophy of History" [Jacob Wang], 2016 (Box 34)
  - First place, Freshman/Sophomore: "Lenz's Claustrophobia" [Jonathan Collazo], 2016 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Graduate: "Das Freiheitsbot; 'Refugeeradio'; A Best Practices Model to Facilitate and Nurture Refugee Narratives" [Rosalie Purvis], 2016 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Graduate: "Kaliszer Spitzen. Erzahlanfang als Problem in Katja Petrowskajas Vielleicht Esther" [Annika Klanke], 2016 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Junior/Senior: "Life, Subjectivity, and Utility in Bach Historiography" [Patrick Braga], 2016 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Freshman/Sophomore: "Une oeuvre extremement belle, une oeuvre qui compte" [Clio Ariane Bowers], 2016 (Box 34)
  - Third place, Junior/Senior: "Losing Lenz: Against Time, Sleep, and Self" [Austin P. Ward], 2016 (Box 34)
  - First place, Junior/Senior: "You Only Need to Change Your Direction: Kafka and Inertia" [Noa Weley], 2017 (Box 34)
  - Second place, Freshman/Sophomore: "Irrationality and Redemption in 'The Burrow'" [Allyson Evans], 2017 (Box 34)
  - First place, Freshman/Sophomore: "Das Selbst: Nu rein Produkt des Staates? Eine Krise der Identitat in Peter Schneiders Roman Der Mauersprinter" [Juliane Scholtz], 2017 (Box 34)
- Series XI. The Graduate Prize in Philosophy
  - Elements from the Eighteenth and the Nineteenth Century in the Philosophy of John Stuart Mill, 1914 (Box 10)
  - Saint Bernard of Clairvaux, by "Bernard Claravallensis" ( James Edwin Creighton ), 1916 (Box 10)
  - Comte and Spencer: A Study of the Social Organism, by Glenn R. Morrow, 1920 (Box 10)
  - A Philosophical Consideration of the Theory of Relativity, by Harold R. Smart, 1921 (Box 10)
  - Emile Boutroux, by Lucy Shepard Crawford, 1922 (Box 10)
  - Hegel's Theory of Absolute Knowledge, by Anna Forbes Liddell, 1923 (Box 10)
  - Logic and Realism in the Law: Mr. Justice Holmes, by Harvey C. Mansfield, 1928 (Box 10)
  - A Study in Psychological Theory, by Carl M. White, 1931 (Box 10)
  - The Unique and the Universal in the Experience of Beauty in Art, by Bertram Morris, 1932 (Box 10)
  - An Introduction to the Timely and Synoptic Elements of Metaphysics, by "Anti-Scala Perfectionis" (H. A. Myers), 1933 (Box 10)
  - Kant's Deduction of the Categories, by Cedric Evans, 1934 (Box 11)
  - Inference in Pragmatic Logic, by Milton H. Williams, 1936 (Box 11)
  - On the Doctrine of Truth and Existence in Descartes, by Alan Gewirtz, 1937 (Box 11)
  - Language and the Structure of Mathematics and Physical Fact, by Robert Eugene Marshak, 1938 (Box 11)
  - Criticism and Comparison of the Empirical Methods of Dewey Alexander and Wittgenstein, by Stuart M. Brown, 1939 (Box 11)
  - An Essay on Leibniz and the Identity of Indiscernibles, by Stuart M. Brown, 1940 (Box 11)
  - The Purpose of the Parmenides, by Atwell R. Turquette, 1942 (Box 11)
  - On Aristotle's Notion of Intuitive Knowledge, by John O'Connor, 1946 (Box 11)
  - Reason, Impartiality and Philosophical Method, by Daniel Kading, 1948 (Box 11)
  - Plato and the Open Society, by Marcus G. Singer, 1949 (Box 11)
  - Sermon on the Self, by William H. Gass, 1950 (Box 11)
  - Prichard, Green, and Moral Obligation, by Charles H. Monson, Jr., 1952 (Box 11)
  - Reason and Conduct in Kant, by I. Cant Badley, 1953 (Box 11)
  - Some Platitudes Concerning Ethics, by I. Cant Badley, 1954 (Box 11)
  - The Circle in Aristotle's Ethics, by Walter O. Pearson, 1955 (Box 11)
  - C. I. Lewis' Analysis of Terms, by David Keyt, 1955 also (Box 11)
  - How is Language Possible, by Sydney Shoemaker, 1956 (Box 11)
  - On the Rationality of Persuading, by John N. Garver, 1957a (Box 11)
  - How do I Know that I Have a Headache?, by Sydney S. Shoemaker, 1957b (Box 11)
  - Private Language, by John Newton Garver, 1958a (Box 11)
  - Some Metaphysical Pictures, by Hugh S. Chandler, 1958b (Box 11)
- Series XII. The Guilford Prize
  - The Social Life of the Crow, by Miss Leonora B. Fletcher, 1903 (Box 12)
  - The Oxford Movement, by E. J. Tucker [George H. Sabine], 1904 (Box 12)
  - The Recent Industrial Conflict in Colorado as Illustrative of Present-day Tendencies in the United States in the Relations of Labor and Capital, by W. W. Gail, 1905 (Box 12)
  - The Problem of the Muscovite, by E. E. Hazard, 1906 (Box 12)
  - Individualism and Present Tendencies in America, by W. A. Shea, 1907 (Box 12)
  - The Painter and the Layman, by A. Layman Painter, 1909 (Box 12)
  - Old Ideals and Selfish Ideals, by Miss Stella Heilbrunn, 1911 (Box 12)
  - The Sophists, by Murray W. Bundy, 1912 (Box 12)
  - A Sojourn in the Primeval, by Philohelos (Mr. Francis Harper ), 1913 (Box 12)
  - The Immigrant and American Labor, by Epictetus (Mr. E. A. deLima ), 1914 (Box 12)
  - Youth the Inquirer, by Albert William Meyer, 1915a (Box 12)
  - The Dualism of the Vision of the Middle Ages and its Consummation in Dante, by Miss Ellen B. Armstrong, 1915b (Box 12)
  - Children of Lillith, by Miss Signe K. Toksvig under the pseudonym of "C. E. Smith", 1916a (Box 12)
  - Virgil and the American School-boy, by Miss Lila V. Stevenson under the pseudonym of "R. S. Monroe", 1916b (Box 12)
  - Concerning Youth, by William E. Seely, 1917 (Box 12)
  - Science, by Mr. William Schack, pseudonym of H. F. Wincon, 1918 (Box 12)
  - Essay on Clio, by Ernest L. Hettich, pseudonym Thornbury, 1919a (Box 12)
  - The Heritage of Revolution, by Barnett Nover, (Alan Tarvey), 1919b (Box 12)
  - The History of an Idea, by Barnet Nover, 1920 (Box 12)
  - Fact and Sense of Fact, by John M. Maloney, pseudonym John Hancock, 1921 (Box 12)
  - Virginia Tobacco, by Miss Thelma F. Brumfield, pseudonym W. K. Carr, 1922 (Box 12)
  - Colors, by Miss Edith W. Parrott, pseudonym Denver Baird, 1923 (Box 12)
  - Our Leaders of the Future, by James Arthur Humphrey, pen name for Putnam J. Jones, 1924 (Box 12)
  - The Poet's Glass, by K. C. Walz, pseudonym Arthur A. Kingsley, 1925-26 (Box 12)
  - The Alchemy of Art, by Hyman Yudewitz, pseudonym Guzano de Seda, 1927-28 (Box 12)
  - Macaulay, by Francis D. Wormuth, 1929 (Box 12)
  - Two English Views of the French Revolution: A Study in the Making of Historic Public Opinion, by Harold A. Lehrman, pseudonym Clinton, 1930 (Box 12)
  - A Criticism of Tolstoy's Theory of Art, by George Burns ( George H. Weltner ), 1932 (Box 12)
  - Guilford Prize not awarded, 1933
  - Didacticism in Lyric Poetry, by Irene Samuel, 1934 (Box 13)
  - Specimens of the Prose of Engelsdrockh, by Argus John Tresidder, 1935 (Box 13)
  - The Apprenticeship of Parliament in the Reign of Elizabeth, by Goldwin Smith, pseudonym Keith Winter, 1936 (Box 13)
  - Sentence of Defeat: a Study of George Gissing, by Christopher Morley, Jr., pseudonym Thomas More, 1937 (Box 13)
  - Pascal: An Essay, by Boris I. Bittker, 1938 (Box 13)
  - Gerard Manley Hopkins, by Howard R. Houston, pseudonym Felix Randall, 1939 (Box 13)
  - The City that Grew from the Desert, by Paul Leighton, 1940 (Box 13)
  - War Babies, by Howard Jay Samuely, pseudonym Lee Conrad, 1942 (Box 13)
  - A. E. Housman, by John Detmold, 1943a (Box 13)
  - In the Hills of Idaho, by Aaron Zucker, pseud. Alan Storm, 1943b (Box 13)
  - Of Dust and Nothing More, by Anita E. W. Monsees, pseud. Caril R. Hewes, 1944 (Box 13)
  - Carlyle's "Revolutions" Lectures, by Roderigo de Triana [ Robert Pearsall ], 1952 (Box 13)
  - In Quest of Myself, by "Searcher", 1953 (Box 13)
  - The Parliamentarianism of the Constitutional Democratic Party in the First State Duma, by William Slany, 1954 (Box 13)
  - The Evolution of My Personal Philosophy, by I. Joel Abramson, 1955 (Box 13)
  - English Prose Specimens, by Lawrence Lipking, 1956 (Box 13)
  - Eliot's Criticism of Metaphysical Poetry, by Sister Thomas Marion, 1957a (Box 13)
  - The Mythology of Self, by Sandra E. Mortola, 1957b (Box 13)
  - Ernest Hemingway & The Spanish Earth, by Richard Freedman, 1958a (Box 13)
  - Selections from Three Essays, by Robert Edward Scholes, 1958b (Box 13)
  - The German Threat to the Concert of Europe, by Lindsley E. Webster, 1959 (Box 13)
  - A Review of H. D. F. Kito's Greek Tragedy, by James French Forrest, 1960a (Box 13)
  - The Burden of Aeneas: John Peale Bishop, by Andrew John Von Hendy, 1960b (Box 13)
  - Engels' Conception of History, by Leonard Kimerman, pseud. Tim Kooper, 1960c (Box 13)
  - Milton's "Lycidas" and Donne's "The Funerall," by Joreth Min Yeeshe, 1961 (Box 14)
  - Dramatic Structure and Symbol in La Dolce Vita, by Hilary Thimmesh, 1962 (Box 14)
  - "Heart of Darkness" and the Failure of the Imagination, by James L. Guetti, Jr., 1963a (Box 14)
  - A Comparison of the Fifth Acts of Othello and The Maid's Tragedy, 1963b (Box 14)
  - A Short View of the Eighteenth-Century Syncretists, by Robert Folkenflik, 1963c (Box 14)
  - Towards a Definition of the Dandy, by Stanley Corngold, 1964a (Box 14)
  - The "Speculatiue and Offic'd Instrument": Reason and Love in Othello by Jared Curtis, 1964b (Box 14)
  - Carlyle and the Epic, by Robert Folkenflik, 1965 (Box 14)
  - W. B. Yeats and "The Shadowy Waters", by Schendley Carstairs ( Jerald L. Bullis ), 1967 (Box 14)
  - Verbal Irony in Literature: A Psychoanalytic Investigation ( Frank Stringfellow ), 1988 (Box 30)
  - Minor Mundus: The Figurative Use of the Body in Pearl ( Kevin Marti ) ["Patrick A. Gesis" pseudonym], 1988 (Box 30)
- Series XIII. The Heermans Prize
  - This Is What Happened, by Charles B. Moss, 1933-1934 (Box 14)
  - Subway Face by "Seymour Abbott Gross" ( Lawrence Abbott ), 1934-5a (Box 14)
  - Dollar Deliriums, by Avery B. Cohan (2nd prize), 1933-1934-5b (Box 14)
  - I Would Found A University, by Violet J. Brown, 1934-5 (Box 14)
  - Nearer My God to Thee, by Robert M. Gorrell, 1935-6 (Box 14)
  - Life of John Doe, by Seymour B. Berkowitz, 1935-6 (Box 14)
  - Barge Baby, by Charles Brunelle (Box 14)
  - Farmers' Holiday, by Boris I. Bitther, 1938 (Box 14)
  - And the Pursuit of Happiness, by Harold E. Johnson, 1938 (Box 14)
  - Intermission, by Harold E. Johnson, 1938 (Box 14)
  - Virgil, by Alexander Zeeve, 1938 (Box 14)
  - Apartment 3D, by Edward L. Kamarck, 1939 (Box 14)
  - Chenango Crone, by Edward L. Kamarck, 1940a (Box 14)
  - Domestic Relations, by Philip Mandel, 1940b (Box 14)
  - Fork in the Road, by Ann Nash, 1941 (Box 14)
  - A Fugue Bacchanal, by Frederick M. Shelley, 1941 (Box 14)
  - The Ballad of Claudius Smith, by Irving R. Merrill, 1941 (Box 14)
  - The Melting Pot and the Woman in Bed, by Frederick Shelley III, 1942a (Box 15)
  - American Pieta, by Albert N. Perretta, 1942b (Box 15)
  - Superman's Wife, by Jacob Regal, 1942 (Box 15)
  - Fair Day Thursday, and Private Performance, by Patricia Colbert, 1943 (Box 15)
  - Retreat, by Walter Scheinman, 1943 (Box 15)
  - Ten Cents' Worth of God-Help-Us, by Katherine Thompson, 1943 (Box 15)
  - Oblivion Is Not Here, by Margaret M. Taylor, 1944 (Box 15)
  - Postwar Planning, by James Breckenridge, 1945 (Box 15)
  - Mea Culpa, by Walter Scheinman, 1946 (Box 15)
  - And the Pursuit of Happiness, by William Work, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Five Characters in Search of Saroyan, by Roy Friedlander, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Alias Edward H. Rullof, by William Work, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Up Sword, by Roy Friedlander, 1946 (Box 15)
  - The Reprieve, by Roy Friedlander, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Tomorrow Without Leave, by Walter Scheinman, 1946 (Box 15)
  - While the Moon Grows Cold, by Walter Scheinman, 1946 (Box 15)
  - He-Keeps-Them-Awake, by David Thompson, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Spoil, by Walter Scheinman, 1946 (Box 15)
  - Adirondack Mile, The Late Adam Fry, by Frank C. Kallen, 1949 (Box 15)
  - A Man's Duty, by A. G. Dower, 1950 (Box 15)
  - The False Teeth, by S. B. Tartaro, 1950 (Box 15)
  - The Muskrat Ramble, by Carl Caruso, 1953 (Box 15)
  - Confessional, by Donald Brederman, 1954 (Box 16)
  - The Man on the Bar Stool, by Alex Panas, 1954 (Box 16)
  - The Barrister's Brownstone, by Jane Plunkett, 1956 (Box 16)
  - A Death in the Family, by Bruce Bloom, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Moon Hound, by Gordon Roston, 1958 (Box 16)
  - Give to Me a Golden Star, by Robert Merritt, 1958 (Box 16)
- Series XIV. Mary B. Knoblaugh Prize. Essays, 19 -19.
  - "Liberté, Egalité, Sororité," by Harriet Johnson ('68), 1941-. 60 pp. Bound multilith copy., 1966-67 (Box 16)
  - "The Role of Upstate New York in the Early Women's Rights Struggle" by Michael K. H. Platzer ('67), 19 -. 33 pp. Orig. typescript., 1969-70 (Box 16)
  - "The Women's Rights Movement in the United States," by Barbara Badian ('73), 1951-. 7 pp. typescript. Miss Badian used assumed name "Meryll" on prize., 1970-71 (Box 16)
  - "The Legal Status of Women in 18th Century America" by Marylynn Salmon, 1974 (Box 16)
  - "The Roots of Liberal Feminism: A Critical Study of John Stuart Mill's 'The Subjection of Women'" by Jane Smith (pen name for Catherine Griffeath ), 1976 (Box 16)
  - "Organized Female Charity: 1797 to 1814" by Catherine Streitwieser, 1977 (Box 16)
- Series XV. The Messenger Prize
  - The Relation of the Socialistic Movement to Human Progress, by Carrie Hartman, 1907 (Box 16)
  - A Factor in Civilization, by Andrew McKay, 1908 (Box 16)
  - The Decline in the Use of Torture in Criminal Procedure, by Miss H. N. Bircholdt, 1911 (Box 16)
  - Modernism and Progress, by J.R. Knipfing, 1911 (Box 16)
  - The American Immigrant - a Force in Modern Progress, by Chalmers, 1914 (Box 16)
  - The Sectaries in Nuremberg: An Episode in the History of Religious Liberty, by Austin Patterson Evans, 1915 (Box 16)
  - Human Perfectibility and the Revolutionary Epoch, by Paul B. Schumm, 1916 (Box 16)
  - The Rise of the Protestants of France to Civil and Religious Freedom, by Hugh MacKenzie, 1920 (Box 16)
  - The Development of Opposition to American Slavery and Disunion in England, by Louis Gottschalk, 1921 (Box 16)
  - An Outline of the Development of Cabinet-Party Government in England, by William Cranborne, pseud., 1922 (Box 17)
  - The Relation of the Privy Council and Parliament from the Accession of Elizabeth to the Death of James I, by David Willson, 1923 (Box 17)
  - The Progress of International Arbitration, by David Greenel, 1924 (Box 17)
  - China and the West, by Pearl S. Buck, 1925 (Box 17)
  - A Study in the Rise of Opposition in the House of Commons, by Edmund Abingdon, 1926 (Box 17)
  - Changing India, by Daniel G. Woodard, 1928 (Box 17)
  - The History of English Thought, a Sketch, by Francis Wormuth, 1929 (Box 17)
  - The Edict of 1787: an Episode in the History of Toleration in France, by John Stewart, 1930 (Box 17)
  - The Growth of the Nation Now Called Bolivia, by William Urbans, 1931 (Box 18)
  - Progress and Natural Justice in Myth and Logical System, by Henry A. Myers, 1932 (Box 18)
  - The Beginnings of Learned Journalism, 1665-1730, by Sherman Barnes, 1933 (Box 18)
  - The French Idea of American Independence, by Robert Palmer, 1934 (Box 18)
  - Manfred of Sicily, by William Bark, 1935 (Box 19)
  - The Treaty of Washington, 1871, by Goldwin Smith, 1936 (Box 19)
  - The Sailors in the Roman Imperial Navy, by Chester Starr, Jr., 1937 (Box 19)
  - Comment on Public Affairs in the Works of Langland and Gower, by Arthur Ferguson, 1938 (Box 19)
  - Evolutionary Ethics in George Eliot and Samuel Butler, by Claude Bissell, 1939 (Box 19)
  - Montesquieu's Interpretation of the English Constituition, by John Stapleton, 1940 (Box 20)
  - An Essay in the History of Natural Religion, by Stuart Brown, Jr., 1941 (Box 20)
  - The Population Growth and Land Pattern of Eastern N.Y., 1790-1808, by David Ellis, 1942 (Box 20)
  - Fifty Years of Discrimination Against Citizen and Alien Japanese in the United States, by Howard Samuely, 1944 (Box 20)
  - The Impact of Greek Rhetorical Theory on Rome: 146-55 B.C., by Helen North, 1945 (Box 20)
  - Petrarch on the Origin and Definition of Poetry, by Giovanni Boccaccio, 1947 (Box 21)
  - The Agnostic Dilemma, by John Palmer, 1955 (Box 21)
  - Bernard De Fontenelle: The Idea of Science in Eighteenth Century France, by L eonard Marsak, 1957 (Box 21)
  - Parmenides and Melissos, by Dorothy Perry, 1957a (Box 21)
- Series XVI Messenger-Chalmers Prize
  - Undergraduate award: Elizabeth K. Hook, "Riots in Axholme: 1626-1695.", 1975 (Box 21)